IELTS Mock Test 1.
You will hear a number of different recordings and you will have to answer
questions on what you hear.
There will be time for you to read the instructions and questions and you will
have a chance to check your work.
All the recordings will be played once only.
The test is in four parts.
Now turn to part one.
Part one.
You will shortly hear a conversation between a prospective tenant calling to
know about some vacant accommodation.
First you have some time to look at questions one to five.
Now we shall begin.
You should answer the questions as you listen because you will not hear the
recording a second time.
Listen carefully and answer questions one to five.
Hello?
Yes, hello.
My name is Roger Peters and I'm looking for an apartment.
I saw your ad in the paper about a vacant flat.
I would like to inquire about it.
Ah, okay.
Yes, I got that ad published.
I do have a vacant flat and it is still available.
Ah, then I do have the right number.
Could you please tell me more about the flat?
From the ad in the paper, it sounds nice.
I'm in dire need of a place to shift to.
Why are you looking for a place to shift?
There are several reasons why I'm looking to move, but most of all, I want to lower
my costs and also move to a place closer to my workplace.
The flat you are offering meets the criteria.
I see.
Where are you living now and how much are you paying for rent?
I'm currently living on the East End off Highland Boulevard.
I live in a two bedroom flat and I'm paying $800 a month plus utilities.
It's in that new tower, you know, Brannan Complex.
Oh, yes, that is an exclusive area.
Indeed, it is.
Can I have a little more information about the flat you offer?
What would you like to know?
Well, how spacious is it?
Well, it's big enough to accommodate a family of four to five members.
It has a living room, two bedrooms, dining room, kitchen, washroom and a spacious balcony.
Well, there are three of us in my family and that sounds like it would suit us nicely.
Is it fully furnished?
What about utilities?
Yes, it's fully furnished and utilities included are water, gas and electricity.
You will have to arrange for your own landline for telephone.
Nice.
And what is the precise location of the building it is housed in?
It's on Flayler's Tower.
It's a fairly new building built two to three years back.
Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions six to ten.
Now listen carefully and answer questions six to ten.
Oh, that sounds great.
How much is the rent?
The rent is five hundred and fifty dollars per month.
Oh, that is going to burn a hole in my pocket.
Well, as I said, it is fully furnished and includes all the utilities.
Yes, you did say that.
Now, if you do pay in advance, say six months in advance, which will be three thousand three
hundred dollars, you'll get a discount of five percent off the total rent.
So this means you want to sign an agreement for six months?
I would prefer this, but you do have the option to pay rent every month.
So the choice is yours.
Well, it would be difficult for me to forecast six months rent in advance.
I'd much rather go from month to month rent.
What about parking?
Parking is available next to the entrance.
And is this a secured parking?
I mean, is there security present?
Yes, of course.
There is a security guard twenty four hours a day at the entrance.
Is there anything else you would like to know?
Yes.
How far is it from the shopping mall?
And is there a park nearby for the children to play?
Well, there is a park and playground on the complex, which the children can play in.
Unfortunately, there is no large mall nearby.
The nearest school is three kilometer away, but they do have a pickup.
There is a fair number of stores nearby for day to day shopping.
And when does this flat get ready to shift?
Well, after you fill out the application
and pass the credit and background check, you could move in about a week.
Ah, OK.
Is there anything else?
Yes, you do need to pay the first month's rent and a security amount of five hundred dollars.
Why is there a security deposit?
Mainly to ensure that you do not leave the apartment in a dilapidated condition.
Is it refundable?
Only if you leave the apartment clean and in good shape.
When can I come by to view the flat and make the arrangements?
We can meet tomorrow.
Very well, I'll come then.
Thank you.
That is the end of part one.
You now have half a minute to check your answers.
Now turn to part two.